[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to PR
stasa automation tutal as you all know I
already published 37 YouTube videos
covering concepts of R and so if you
take it as an advanced level Concepts
already published 22
this is our lesson 38 in terms of tasa
automation Concepts and this is our
lesson 23 in terms of advanced level
Concepts in this lesson I'm going to
teach you how can you perform the string
operations trim and replay while
automating your web application I'm
going to teach you these two operations
in
solving one obstacle scenario while
automating your web application and this
is your part one of string operations
soon I'm going to publish part two of
string operations with more operations
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you so now let us jump onto
the system and see how can we perform
these string operations in solving one
obstacle
scario let us first understand what is
the
obstacle where we need to use the string
operations like trim and replace so I'm
just logging into demo webshop as usual
so once you log into demo webshop let me
order one blue jeans okay I'm just
adding into cart and go to shopping cart
and check out the do jeans and provide
all the billing address shipping address
and shipping method and all payment
details okay so once you provide all the
payment details and then I'm going to
confirm the order so as soon as I
confirm the order see I'm going to get
the order number right so now I want to
extract only order number out of this
entire text that means I want to trim
some of the spaces and I want to also
remove these numerical
values and the colon value but I want to
just extract the number from this entire
text how can we do that to automate or
to overcome this challenge let us go to
your trient tasa and see how can we
automate this okay so now
exercises create one fold folder called
string
operations part
one and
here let me create one test
case I'll
say
order number
extraction okay this is our test case
now if you go to modules so what I did
we already
scan the module for the order
confirmation you see this is the order
confirmation module okay in this
module the only change what we did is
this is the order number right this is
the order number this is the object for
the order number and entire text so only
change what we did is for the outer text
after order number colon I've just
introduced star means I just entered the
regular expression because this number
keeps on changing okay so now let's go
back to our test case so let me bring
module to the right side so that I can
create test Case by using the
module so now I want to drag and drop
this order successful
module okay now let me expand this so
what I want to do
here in order number I want
to store the inner text into your buffer
okay let me store this into a buffer
called
order success message this is not order
number but it is order success message
with order number correct I'll say
instead of order
success message okay let it keep it as
order success but here I want to store
this into a buffer
so now let me run this and see what
buffer value we are going to get run
it it's going to extract this entire
text right I want to show you what does
it
contain it extracted the content of this
entire module let's go to
rasa and here
if you see
here You observe
closely see this particular text it has
what this entire value I can see there
are some white spaces or blank spaces
and order number column and then some
text again some blank spaces correct so
now I want to trim all these blank
spaces and I want
to remove this numeric content and I
want to extract only numeric part how
can I do that first I'll be using trim
to remove all these P spaces and I'm
going to use replace I'm going to
replace this entire numeric content
including
colon with a white space with a wi space
so that the trim function can trim
entire white space along with this
numeric portion because the numeric
portion is being repl with the white
space so trim function will replace trim
the white space and then you will have
only order number okay so now let's go
back to our CH Tas so here let me add
another step called
tbox set
tbx set buffer okay I'm going to set the
buffer now why I want to set the buffer
here saying now I want to extract only
order number from where from this
message okay order success message so
I'm going to use one simple formula here
I'm going to copy this formula because I
don't want to enter entire formula here
so let me do one thing let me put this
as let me rename this as buffer so that
you'll understand bore I'm going to do
this way okay copy this so this is my
buffer okay I'm going to replace the
buffer name here okay so I'm going to
use this entire text I'm going to
explain you what is the formula okay
here what I am instructing
tasa so
simply what I'm
saying open curly braces trim what I
want to
trim first I am replacing the
string what is the actual text this
entire mage message whatever I'm storing
in buffer okay that is
my destination message and I want to use
this entire message and what is
the text that you want to replace I want
to replace order number
colon so that's why I'm specifying that
in a square bracket order number colon I
want to replace this what I want to
replace this by a
blank open C Open Bracket and close
bracket that means I want to replace
this with a white space I want to
replace order number colon with white
space and I'm ignoring the case that
means if you enter order number colon
capital W capital N or whatever if you
are entering in a capital letters or if
you are entering in a small letters it's
going to ignore the case it going to
ignore and it going to replace
everything with white space so that's
why I'm ignoring the case and once you
replace order number colon with the
white space and then I am using the trim
function that means it's going to trim
entire white
space along with the white space that we
replaced by using string
replace okay so as soon as you do this
way it's going to format this way trim
string replace what is the string that
we are
considering the string whatever we are
storing here into a buffer that string
and part of the string is order number
colon I want to replace this with a
small white space and I'm ignoring the
case okay so now let me run run this
entire test case now and see what
happens run this
first it stores the value into buffer
and then it uses the formula that we
entered by using buffer value so let me
see here you see tbx so it stored the
white spaces and everything as I told
you earlier now we are creating a new
buffer called order number and we are
extracting only numeric portion see here
buffer with name order number has set to
what
15667 let's go to screen 1561 167 that
means it trimmed entire white spaces and
it replaced order number with one white
space right so it took only numeric
portion right so that means the we
achieved this obstacle by using trim and
replace functions so if you have any
queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries this is our part one of string
operation okay so hope you all
understand how can you perform trim and
replace string operations while
automating your test cases so I'm going
to publish part two of string operations
where I'm going to cover uh more and
more operations to automate your test
case
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish
more thank
[Music]
you